Finding aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) Films and Videotapes, 1930s and 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library
- Series I
  - Singer's Art, The, (Thirteen part series takes the viewer inside the world of the concert and opera singer features UM music student and faculty.)
    - To Music, 1969; [851831-I-59-1]; (Program 1 looks at the problems of interpretation of music and words. Bassett's composition "To Music" is featured. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Harold Haugh, UM-Music; Leslie Bassett, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #649
    - We Seem to Be One, 1969; [851831-I-59-2]; (The demands of the recital on the singer and pianist are demonstrated in performances of selected songs form "Die Shone Mullerin" by Schubert. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #650
    - La Bonne Chanson, 1969; [851831-I-59-3]; (Art songs written by the contemporary American composers Samuel Barber and John Gruen are examined. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #652
    - The Human Instrument, 1969; [851831-I-59-5]; (The voice in the small instrumental ensemble, solo voice, wind instruments and piano. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #653
    - Making Music Together, 1969; [851831-I-59-6]; (The skills and artistic qualities required in a concert presentation of the solo ensemble are examined. The Michigan Chamber Soloist perform. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Willis Patterson, UM-Music; Oscar Henry, EMU-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #654
    - A Blend of Voices, 1969; [851831-I-59-7]; (The challenges of the singer in the small choir. Works by Bach and R. Schuman are performed by the Michigan Chamber Choir. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Thomas Hilbish, UM-Music; Michigan Chamber Choir)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #656
    - Praise and Song, 1969; [851831-I-59-8]; (The University of Michigan Men's Glee Club sings classical contemporary and collegiate songs. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Willis Patterson, UM-Music; Men's Glee Club)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #657
    - Ye People, Listen, 1969; [851831-I-59-9]; (An examination of the solo contata of the late Baroque period featuring performances by UM faulty artists. Features: Leslie Guin, Rosemary Russel, N. Hauenstein, G. Rosseels, Charles Fisher, Lawrence Hurst)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #658
    - With All Thy Heart, 1969; [851831-I-59-10]; (The oratoria - sacred music for chorus, soloist and orchestra - is examined. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Harold Haugh, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #659
    - So Full of Shapes Is Fancy, 1969; [851831-I-59-11]; (Some instruction of the how's of acting and singing featuring opera instructors from the UM Music School. Features: Theo Alcantara, Katherine Hilgengerg, Eva Likova, Robert Luscomb, all UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #660
    - An Illusion of reality, 1969; [851831-I-59-12]; (An examination of the recitative song (sung dialogue) in opera featuring selections from Verdi's "La Traviata," Gluck's "Orfeo," and Mozart's "Marriage of Figaro." Features: John McMollum, UM-Music; Eva Likova, UM-Music; Ralph Herbert, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #661
    - The Impresario, 1969; [851831-I-59-13]; (A performance of Mozart's humorous light opera "The Impresario" featuring the UM Opera Orchestra and student singers. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Theo Alcantara, UM-Music; Eva Likova, UM-Music)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #662
    - A Symphony of Sounds, 1969; [851831-I-59-14]; (A look at the life of a community choral organization and the problems of concert management featuring the directors of the University Musical Society and the Michigan Choral Union. Features: John McCollum, UM-Music; Gail Rector, Donald Bryant)
      - Original:, 2-inch video #663
List of Abbreviations for University Uits
Anthro. -- Department of Anthropology
Arch. -- School of Architecture
Art -- Department of Art or School of Art
Astro. -- Department of Astronomy
Ath. -- Division of Athletics
Bio. Sci. -- Department of Biological Sciences
BIR -- Bureau of Industrial Research
Botany -- Department of Botany
Bus. -- School of Business Administration
Class. -- Department of Classical Studies
Comp. -- Dept. of Computer Science or Computing Center
Econ. -- Department of Economics
Ed. -- School of Education
Eng. -- College of Engineering
Engl. -- Department of English
Ext. -- University Extension Service
F E Lang -- Department of Far Eastern Languages
Geog. -- Department of Geography
Geol. -- Department of Geology
Geron. -- Institute of Gerontology
Hist. -- Department of History
Hum. Gen. -- Department of Human Genetics
ILIR -- Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations
ISMRRD -- Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities
ISR -- Institute for Social Research
IST -- Institute of Science and Technology
Jour. -- Department of Journalism
Law -- Law School
Lib. Sci. -- School of Library Science
LSA -- College of Literature Science and the Arts
Math -- Department of Mathematics
Med. -- School of Medicine and/or University Hospital
MMRC -- Michigan Media Resources Center
Music -- School of Music
Pharm. -- Department of Pharmacy
Phil. -- Department of Philosophy
Phy. Ed. -- Department of Physical Education
Pol. -- Department of Political Science
Pres. -- UM President
Psych. -- Department of Psychology
PTP -- Professional Theater Program
Russ. -- Department of Russian Studies
SNR -- School of Natural Resources
Soc. -- Department of Sociology
SW -- School of Social Work
Speech -- Department of Speech
SPH -- School of Public Health
TVC -- Television Center
VP -- University Vice President
VPAA -- Vice President for Academic Affairs
Zool. -- Department of Zoology